

# TRAN HOANG PHUOC

MARKET INTELLIGENCE

18/04/1996 •

Go Vap District, HCMC **?** 

089 996 7575 📞

tranhoangphuoc18@gmail.com

fb.com/tranhoangphuoc1996

## CAREER OBJECTIVES

I started to change my career path after realizing that teaching was not suitable for me. In the beginning of my job as a Sales Administrator, I continuously learned and supplemented my knowledge of Microsoft Excel in order to process various reports to meet the demands of customers and management. After more than 3 years working in the retail industry, in addition to being proficient in Excel, I continued to learn how to use Power BI to process large amounts of raw data and visualize data to serve reporting for the line manager and strategy team. To serve my career path focused on data processing, I will further enhance my knowledge on using SQL or other data querying tools in the near future.

## **SKILL**

Microsoft Exel

. . . . . . . . . . .

Microsoft Power Query

Microsoft Power BI



English



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

01/2022 - 03/2023

#### AQUA ELECTRICAL APPLIANCES VIETNAM CO. LTD

#### Market Intelligence Specialist

- Build and develop a system with the overseas IT team to support over 500 field staffs, including tasks such as timekeeping, sales reporting, product display reporting, and other extended functions, to replace the outdated system.
- Manage, operate and upgrade the sales reporting system for sales partners. Easily bring benefits to partners when participating in sales programs with AQUA, expanding distribution networks, consulting, and selling. The number of stores participating in the program, which was initially set at nearly 1,500 stores, has increased to over 2,400 stores. The growth in the amount of products sold in 2022 reached 110% compared to 2021.
- Utilize available raw data to create analytical reports on business performance and market share for product display in key economic regions using tools such as Excel, Power Query, and visualise the reports with Power BI to monitor and reduce ineffective store chains in order to focus on expanding more promising store chains.
- Participate in providing input for promotional programs during the peak selling season, designing a blueprint for the system and predicting potential risks that may occur during the program's implementation. Work together with the IT team to promptly provide updates, fix system errors, and support customers after the program ends. With easy participation and reward acquisition, the program has achieved its target of increasing the amount of products sold and has also been able to address the issue of inventory surplus.

#### 04/2020 - 12/2021

#### ARCHTRADE CO., LTD & SPIRAL CO. LTD

#### Sale Administrator

Working on the AQUA project:

- When the project is transferred from ARCHTRADE to SPIRAL at 10/2020, I am still willing to follow the project to ensure a smooth transition process in terms of providing data and ensuring the benefits of the sales force team.
- Generating reports related to Display, Out of Stock, and Sell Out metrics in order to report the status of goods to higher authorities in a timely manner so that they can be processed promptly.
- Participating in building an incentive bonus template for the sales force team in the market and being the main person responsible for calculating monthly bonuses as well as bonuses for special incentive programs for employees in order to timely disburse them and create motivation for the sales force team.
- Resolve urgent report requests from customers or line managers quickly, regardless of the time.
- Participate in collecting feedback from the sales force team to convey their needs to the IT team in order to serve the construction of a simple but optimised management system for data collection.



09/2019 - 03/2020

#### ACACY CO. LTD

#### Sale Administrator

Working on the Samsung project, my responsibilities include:

- Compiling reports on various aspects such as Display, Out of Stock, Sell Out Competitor, Price & Promotion.
- Reviewing and verifying the accuracy of the data uploaded onto the Acacy system.
- Collaborating with team leaders to ensure the data is complete and accurate.
- Fulfilling any other requests from the management as needed.

## REFERENCE

#### Ms. Phan Thi Mai Anh

Market Intelligence Manager AQUA ELECTRICAL APPLIANCES VIETNAM

0349986062 - anh.phanthimai@aquavietnam.vn

#### Mr. Vo Thanh Trung

Senior Sales Operation ONE MOUNT GROUP

0934044539 - <u>trung.vo@onemount.com</u>

## **EDUCATION**

Q

09/2014 - 06/2018

#### **HUE UNIVERSITY OF EDUCATION**

**Pedagogy of Languages** 

Graded: 7,5

## **CERTIFICATE**

**TOEIC** (10/05/2018)

Reading & Listening - Score: 835/990

Speaking - Score: 120/200; Writing - Score: 180/200

**Power Bl Basic & Advance** (15/03/2023)

From: CSC.EDU.VN Final Test Score: 7/10

#### **HOBBY**